Bye-bye.
I just got us
reservations at Michel's
and tickets to The Music Man
to celebrate
our first holiday season
as a be-troth-ed couple.
"Betrothed."
Betrothed couple.
Hey.
Hi.
Ah...
Oh...
Pheebs?
Huh?
Skull?
Oh, yeah, it's my mom's.
Oh, my God!
No, no, no, it's not,
it's not my mom.
It belonged to my mom.
Yeah, no, she
used to put it out
every Christmas
to remind us
that even though it's Christmas
people still die...
and, you can put
candy in it.
( giggles )
Hey.
Licorice?
Sure.
Hey, I just found out
I get Ben
for the holidays this year.
Oh.
That's great.
You going
to dress up as Santa?
Nope.
I mean,
I know Susan does every year
but I think I want
to take this year
to teach him all about Hanukkah.
And maybe I could teach
Ben about the Christmas skull
and how people die.
You may need to use this year
to teach Ben about Phoebe.
Hmm.
Hey.
Did you know he was in there?
No.
How long have we been home?
About a half an hour.
Lovely.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's DOA ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Hey, you know
what I was thinking?
When we get married,
are you going to, uh...
Change your
last name to Bing?
No.
Why not?
Bing's weird.
Oh, hey, you guys.
Hi.
Can I have one to go?
Guess what?
My landlord just called
and my apartment's going
to be ready soon
so I guess I'll be moving out.
Aw, Phoebe, I'm
going to miss you.
Yes, you will be very sad.
All right, well...
I got to go
tell Rachel the good news.
Oh, you guys going to be
living together again?
Yeah, why not?
Well, she's having
so much fun with Joey
I just assumed she'd still
be living with him.
Why do you think she's having
so much fun living with Joey?
No reason except...
she... told me.
Really?
So she said she didn't
want to live with me anymore?
No, no, she
didn't say that.
I think you should
talk to Monica now.
Phoebe, don't
worry about it.
I'm sure she wants
to live with you.
You're sure?
You're absolutely sure?
Well, no, but she
probably does.
Oh, probably?
Yeah, I don't like that word.
Look, I know what
"probably" really means.
Yeah, uh-huh, yeah.
Oh, your mom probably won't
kill herself, you know?
Oh, you know
I'm sorry, but I'm not
hanging all my hopes
of Rachel and I living together
on-on-on "probably," you know?
You got to take care of yourself
in this world, you know?
If history teaches us nothing.
"Bing" doesn't seem
so weird now, does it?
( door opening )
Hey, great, you're home.
Guess what Phoebe
got me for Christmas?
( cymbal crash )
Drums?
No, drums!
Hi.
Could we get two burritos
to go, please?
I'm sorry-- but
not that sorry
because you don't
have to live with it.
We have a reservation under
the name Chandler Bing.
Okay, we'll have a table for you
in about 45 minutes.
45 minutes?
We have tickets
to The Music Man at 8:00.
I'm sorry. Christmas
is a very busy time, sir.
Is this because
of the burrito thing?
You need to
give him money.
Give him money?
It was a joke.
No, to get a table.
Places like this are
always shaking you down.
Everybody wants
a payoff.
All right, calm down, O'Malley.
I'll slip him some money.
All right, but you've got
to be smooth about it.
Hey, I can be smooth.
Listen, we're in
a little bit of a
hurry, so if you could
get us a table a little
quicker, I'd appreciate it.
Of course, sir.
Okay.
How'd it go?
Had the money
in the wrong hand.
Whoo...
( laughing )
Hey, you don't feel
like you're going
to throw up, do you?
No.
Well, I do, so let's...
So, Ben, you, uh...
you know what holiday
is coming up, don't you?
Christmas.
Yeah, and you know
what other holiday
is coming up?
Christmas Eve.
Yes, but also...?
Hanukkah.
See, you're part Jewish
and-and Hanukkah
is a Jewish holiday.
Santa has reindeers
that can fly.
Right, but on Hanukkah...
Hanukkah's the
celebration
of a miracle.
See, years and years ago
there were these people
called the Maccabees.
♪ Jingle bells,
jingle bells... ♪
Okay.
That's right, yes, but
on Hanukkah, we sing, uh...
♪ Dreidel, dreidel, dreidel,
I made you out of clay... ♪
♪ Rudolph
the red-nosed reindeer...♪
Okay, it's not a contest.
When is Santa coming?
Well, how about this
year, instead of Santa
we have fun
celebrating Hanukkah?
No Santa?
Was I bad?
No. Oh, no, no. Hey.
You weren't bad.
You've been very good, Ben.
Santa's mad at me.
Hey, hey. Come on.
Ben, Santa is not
mad at you, okay?
Hey, you're his
favorite little guy.
So Santa's coming?
Yes.
Santa's coming.
It's easy. Just
keep it casual.
Give him a kind word
shake his hand
and give him the money.
How do you know
so much about this?
I don't know.
Richard used to do it,
didn't he?
We'd be eating
our soup right now.
Mustache bastard.
Okay, those
people just left.
Come on. Quick,
give him the money.
We'll get their table.
Excuse me.
We're in a bit
of a hurry.
Certainly,
right this way.
Ah, ha-ha-ha.
( drums and cymbals playing )
Ha!
So you like the drums?
That's... that's great.
You know, I was worried that
you know, they would create
maybe an unbearable
living situation, but...
okay, well,
apparently not, so, yay!
Hey, hey, Pheebs,
check it out.
We already learned
a song. Ready?
One, two,
three, four.
Tequila!
That's fun.
Here you go.
Thank you, Gunther.
Put her there.
( coins clanking )
Definitely not
easier with coins.
Thank you.
Oh, hey, Pheebs.
Here.
Now I only owe you $49.50.
Thanks.
Hey.
Hey, Pheebs.
If you want to get Joey
a Christmas present
that disrupts
the entire building
why not get him something
a little bit more subtle
like a wrecking ball
or a vial of small pox
to release
in the hallway?
It's not just
the drum noise.
Every five minutes
Joey throws his sticks
in the air
and I have to hear,
"Oh, my eye!
Oh, God, my eye!"
I mean, it is so annoying.
Yes, thank you.
You see,
this is how normal people
are supposed to react to drums.
Wait a minute...
Phoebe, you got Joey drums
to annoy Rachel
so she wouldn't want
to live there anymore?
Maybe on some level.
Joey, you know
that you could just not
throw the sticks
up in the air.
What is rock 'n' roll
about that?
Hey, Joey.
I got you another present.
Oh, wait, before you
tell me what it is...
( drum roll )
( cymbals crash )
Okay, what is it?
It's a... tarantula!
Oh...
God.
Rachel, what... I'm sorry.
What was I thinking
giving Joey
this big, gross, scary spider
in such a poorly
constructed cage?
What are you
talking about?
I love them.
I had a tarantula
when I was a kid
but it died because my
cat ate it, and then...
then my cat died,
but, Joey, isn't this cool?
Is it on me?
I feel like it's on me.
I got, I got...
Oh, isn't that adorable?
Joey is afraid of the tarantula.
Oh, God.
He's so adorable.
God, he's just
so much fun.
Joey's the best.
I'm glad you're having
so much fun here.
Whoa, wait, wait a minute.
What...?
Phoebe, what's the matter?
Our apartment is ready.
And that makes you angry
because...?
Because you would rather
live here with Joey.
Where did you get that?
Monica and Chandler said that
you were having so much fun here
and apparently no amount
of drums or tarantulas
is going to change that.
Phoebe...
Hmm?
Did you get
all this stuff for Joey
to try and drive me
out of the apartment?
Honey, if you wanted
to do that, you might as well
just have gotten him a fish.
You know how fish freak me out.
Ah... fish.
But it wouldn't
have mattered anyway, Phoebe.
You and I are going
to live together.
We're roommates--
that's the deal.
Yes, but I wanted you
to want to live with me
but, okay, if you're having
so much fun over here...
Oh, it's so much
more fun with you.
We did have fun, didn't we?
We did.
Yeah.
Well, anyway, they say
if we want,
we could see it tonight.
Oh, I would love to.
Yeah, okay.
Oh, good, great.
All right, good.
Oh, and, Monica asked me
to make the drumming stop.
Um...
Hmm...
Done.
Hey.
Hello, sir.
You here to return
those pants?
No, these are my pants.
Oh.
Okay.
How can I help you?
Do you have a Santa outfit left?
Two days
before Christmas?
Sorry, man.
Okay, look, do you have
anything, uh, Christmas-y?
I promised my son
and I really don't want
to disappoint him.
Um... come on...
you got to have something.
I'm the Holiday Armadillo!
I'm a friend of Santa's
and he sent me here
to wish you a merry Christmas.
What happened to Santa,
Holiday Armadillo?
Santa was unavailable
so close to Christmas.
Oh, well, come in,
have a seat.
You must be exhausted
coming all the way from...
Texas.
Texas?
That's right, Ben.
I'm Santa's representative
for all the southern states
and... Mexico!
But Santa sent me here
to give you
these presents, Ben.
Maybe the lady will help me
with these presents.
Wow, thanks.
You're welcome, Ben.
Merry Christmas.
Ooh, and Happy Hanukkah.
Are you for Hanukkah, too?
Because I'm part Jewish.
( gasps ):
You are? Me, too!
Because armadillos also
wandered in the desert?
You want to wander
in the hall?
Hey, Ben, what if
the Holiday Armadillo
told you all about
the Festival of Lights?
Cool!
Come on, Ben.
Years and years ago
there were these people
called the Maccabees.
Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas.
Santa!
Hey.
What are you
doing here, Santa?
Well, I'm here to see
my old buddy, Ben.
What are you doing here...
weird... turtle man?
I'm the Holiday Armadillo
your part Jewish friend.
You sent me here
to give Ben some
presents, remember?
What?
Did you bring me
any presents, Santa?
You bet I did, Ben.
Put her there.
Well, it would've worked
this time
if his hands weren't
so damned small.
Ho, ho, ho!
Ben, why don't you
open more presents
and Santa,
the Armadillo and I
will have a little talk
in the kitchen.
There's a sentence
I never thought I'd say.
What are you doing?
You called everyone and said
you were having trouble
finding a Santa costume
so I borrowed one
from a guy at work.
Thank you,
but-but you got to leave.
Why?
Because I'm finally getting him
excited about Hanukkah
and you're wrecking it.
But I didn't get
to shake my belly
like a bowlful of jelly.
I'm sorry, Chandler
but this... this is
really important to me.
Okay, fine.
I'll give the suit back.
Hey.
You think you can
keep it another night?
Santa? Really?
Yeah, is that okay?
Did your dad ever
dress up like Santa?
No.
Then it's okay!
Okay, Ben,
Santa has to go.
Say good-bye.
No, why does he have to go?
Because if Santa and
the Holiday... Armadillo...
are ever in the same
room for too long
the universe will implode.
Merry Christmas!
No, why can't
the Armadillo leave?
I want Santa.
Fine, I give up.
Santa, Santa can stay.
Well, I'll stay
but only because
I want to hear about Hanukkah.
Ben
will you sit here with Santa
and learn about Hanukkah?
Okay, Santa.
( whispers ):
Thank you.
You're welcome.
All right...
it's time for the story
of Hanukkah.
Years and years ago
there were these people
called the Maccabees.
Merry Christmas!
Oh, wow.
Look at this place.
Oh, this is terrible.
Oh, they've made so many changes
I can't even feel my
grandmother's presence anymore.
Ooh, new sconces.
Oh, my God!
What?
Okay, remember, uh,
remember how you told me
that your grandmother
put up that wall
to make that
into two bedrooms?
Yeah?
And remember
you said you were afraid
the landlord would find out
and tear it down?
Yeah?
Do you really not know
where I'm going with this?
It left.
It's one huge room.
Oh, no.
( gasps )
Wow!
See?
Well, I guess we'll just
have to put the wall back up.
You can't,
because of the new skylight.
There's a skylight?
Wow!
Oh, so what should we do?
Should we start looking
for a new place?
You know, I'm sensing
that my grandmother
would not be comfortable
with that.
Oh, yeah?
Starting to feel her again
there, are we?
A little bit, yeah.
Yeah...
Pheebs, is your
grandmother
maybe saying
that you should
live here alone?
You heard it, too?
You have the gift.
Phoebe, it's okay.
I like living with Joey.
Are you sure?
Oh, please--
I hate packing,
it's closer to work
and we do have fun.
Although, I'm really going
to miss living with you.
Oh, me, too.
I know.
Oh, oh, wait, did you
hear that? Listen...
Huh?
I'm getting something
from your grandmother.
She said that since
you get to keep the
one-bedroom apartment
you should give Rachel
the purple chair?
No, I do not hear that.
And the miracle was that
that little bit of oil
that should have
lasted just one day
burned for...
Eight whole days.
That's right.
And that's why we
celebrate Hanukkah.
The end.
Awesome.
My favorite part
was when Superman
flew all the Jews
out of Egypt.
The armadillo
was actually
not so thrilled
about that part.
Okay, Ben
it's time to light
the Hanukkah candles!
Oh, ho, ho.
Hey...
Oh, wow.
Looks like the Easter
Bunny's funeral in here.
Come on, come on,
we're lighting the candles.
Come on.
Oh.
Okay, I understand
why Superman is here
but why is there a porcupine
at the Easter Bunny's funeral?
Joey:
Did you get it?
I got it.
Is it back in the cage?
It's back in the cage.
Is the cage closed?
Joey, will you just
come out here
and stop being such a baby?!
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]